Welcome to Professor Dave Explains.
I’m Dave, and this channel is for learning.
There are a lot of YouTube channels for learning,
but this one is different.
I’m not going to dazzle you with science-flavored
edutainment that’s fun to watch but falls
short at delivering real knowledge.
I’m also not going to just stand here and
lecture at a blackboard for two hours at a time.
I want to give you something in between.
The shortest, easiest route there has ever
been to a working understanding of everything
around you, from the infinitesimally small
to the incomprehensibly large.
I want to teach you chemistry, so you can
understand atoms and molecules.
I want to teach you biochemistry, so you can
understand big molecules, like proteins and DNA.
I want to teach you biology, so you can understand
the components that make up living organisms.
I want to teach you physics, so you can understand the way the universe works on the most fundamental level.
I want to teach you astronomy, so you can
understand all the fascinating objects we
can see in this great big universe.
I want to teach you mathematics, so you can
understand the important calculations that
scientists have to perform, and reproduce them yourself.
And that’s just the tip of the iceberg.
But why bother learning all this stuff?
Well for one thing, when you read about science-related
news, regarding nutrition, or medicine, or
technology, wouldn’t you like to know what’s
going on?
To make informed decisions for yourself, rather
than just repeating what others are saying?
The only way to get there is to learn the
fundamentals, and this channel is the fastest
way to do it.
I cover typical high school and undergraduate
curricula, so if you’re a student, stick around.
I will explain exactly what you are learning
in class in ways that will finally make sense.
My tutorials are succinct, with animations
geared towards maximizing comprehension rather
than amusement, and they stress the most important
details, while skipping all the fluff.
It’s like I took your textbook and I’m
giving you the cliffs notes version, in easy-to-watch
segments.
And the best news is that because I focus
on the main concepts, my content is also great
for anyone who just wants to learn science
without having to go to school or read a lot
of books, and no prior knowledge is assumed.
I’ll start you at the very beginning with
general chemistry, and you can climb the ladder
from there.
You may not find any explosions or songs or
flashy gimmicks along the way, but we don’t
have time for that, we are here to understand
the universe, which is pretty fun in its own right.
And it doesn’t matter who you are, either.
Education is for everyone, and you should
want it, because knowledge is cool.
With knowledge comes wisdom, and if everyone
can get wise enough, we can mold the world
as we see fit.
So subscribe to my channel for updates about
new content, support me on Patreon so I can
make lots of it as fast as possible, and let’s
learn some science.